Ahmed Mohamed Reda

Front-End Developer

(+20) 1145809984

□ asayed565565@gmail.com

♥ Giza

in ahmedmohamed165

SUMMARY

Mid-Leve front-end with 2 years of experience building websites and web applications using ReactJS and modern JavaScript tools/frameworks. Seeking a challenging and rewarding position as a full stack developer where I can apply my skills in programing to deliver high-quality solutions.

EDUCATION

- Bachelor of commerce English section

2016-2020 Cairo University Accounting department GPA: 2.8 (70%)

Front End Developer (React.js)

October 2023 - February 2024 Route Academy

EXPERIENCE

Merchandise Developer & Help Desk

February 2021 - December 2023

ACTIV ABOU ALAA

Key Qualifications & Responsibilities

- Merchandise Developer & control
 - Review & check the new merchandise and collecting data about it like (supplier description - cost price - quantity) to activate & coding it into the system
 - Adjustment prices of the merchandise on the program (discount / sale)
 - Main member in stocktaking committee
- Help Desk
 - Follow-up computers for employees
 - Installation and operation of new devices and installation of refrigerators and operating systems
 - Ensuring security and efficiency of IT infrastructure
 - Install and configure software and hardware
 - Set up accounts and workstations

System Administration

February 2018 – June 2020

JEL ACTIV

Key Qualifications & Responsibilities

- Installing and configuring software, hardware and networks
- Monitoring system performance and troubleshooting issues
- Ensuring security and efficiency of IT infrastructure
- Install and configure software and hardware
- Set up accounts and workstations
- Monitor performance and maintain systems according to requirements

PERSONAL ACHIEVEMENT

#louvreinnovations

Overview: site for interior decoration works company, display their bio & projects

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript

#Yummy

Overview: Discover new and interesting cooking recipes on this website! The website offers a diverse range of recipes organized by region, ingredient, and meal type, making it easy to find exactly what you're looking for.

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, API, jQuery

#Egyptian party

Overview: a simple responsive website using jQuery

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery

#Weather App

Overview: The Weather-Forecast JS app is a user-friendly web tool for checking real-time weather forecasts. Developed with, it uses a weather API to provide users with essential details like temperature, and wind speed. And geolocation API to access the user's location information with their permission.

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, API

#Login APP

Overview: A simple App This system consists of:

- 1- Sign-up form for users to register with a unique email address, name, and password.
- 2- Sign-in form for logging in with email and password.
- 3- Home page displaying the user's name upon successful sign-in.

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Font Awesome

#Bookmarker

Overview: A user-friendly website URL bookmarker that allows you to save and organize your favorite websites with ease.

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Font Awesome, CRUD Logic

#Random Quotes

Overview: JS application generates random quotes.

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript

#DANIAL

Overview: Portfolio site, it's a fully responsive website featuring seven sections and a

user-friendly navbar **Tools**: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

TRAINING - COURSES

Online Courses

- IT Help desk - Web Development (El-Zero) - Master Python (El-Zero)

• Python Diploma [Flask-Django Frameworks]

September 2022 – December 2022 IT Sharks

SKILLS

Software Skills:

Languages: Python - HTML – CSS - Java Script - SCSS - TypeScript

- **Libraries:** React.js – jQuery

- **Frameworks:** Bootstrap

- Tools: GitHub - VS Code - Figma

Language skills:

- Arabic [Mother tongue] - English [Very Good]

Personal skills:

- Problem solving skills. - Team player

- Excellent Communication Skills - Research & Analysis

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

- Date of birth: 16th May 1998 - Military status: Exempted